# Christopher J. Warner II, Ph.D.

linkedin.com/in/chris-warner-II

chris-warner-ii.github.io
cwarner@berkeley.edu

## Summary

Computational neuroscientist and biophysicist with a passion for data science and machine learning. With a decade of expertise in the field, I enjoy systems level thinking and excel where technical ability and creativity are both required to bring various inputs together into algorithmic solutions.

#### Skills

Expertise: Building machine learning algorithms (neural networks, regression, classification, clustering), dynamical systems modelling, Graph Theory, Bayesian inference, visual neuroscience and image processing, time-series analysis Technology: Python, MATLAB, Labview, Mathematica, R, C++, Git, Docker, AWS, [Pytorch, Scikit-learn, Pandas, ...]

# Experience

## Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory

Oct 2023 - Present

Postdoctoral Researcher, Affiliate

- Characterized vocal complexity by computing Predictive Information on human speech TIMIT dataset
- Trained CNN model to classify spoken phoneme based on from recorded spectrogram from TIMIT dataset

## CODA Biotherapeutics

Jul 2021 - Mar 2022

Machine Learning Engineer, Consultant

- Delivered full ML algorithm to predict interactions between proteins and drugs including NLP implementation
- Interfaced with biologists to guide protein synthesis; incorporating their feedback to guide model development
- Transitioned project into production by leveraging cloud computing, containerization and process engineering

## University of California, Berkeley

Sep 2011 - Sep 2019

Redwood Center for Theoretical Neuroscience, Graduate Student Researcher

- Pioneered retina-like image segmentation algorithm based on network modularity and anisotropic diffusion
- Built Bayesian latent variable model to infer unobserved cell assembly structure in spiking neural data
- Mentored undergrad students, guiding them in projects analyzing real world social network and global trade data

#### MIT, Lincoln Laboratory

Sep 2005 - Feb 2009

Advanced RF Techniques & Systems Group, Electrical Engineer

- Spearheaded radar program through hardware dev, software integration, testing, data collection, analysis and results
- Created statistical analysis pipeline to detect and classify moving targets under foliage using radar signature
- Tested, maintained and fielded electronic moving target simulator hardware units for radar system calibration

#### Education

#### University of California, Berkeley

Ph.D., Biophysics and Computational Neuroscience

Ohio State University

B.S., Physics

Berkeley, CA Sep 2011 - Sep 2019

Columbus, OH

Sep 2001 - Jul 2005

### **Selected Publications**

Warner, C., Ruda, K., Sommer, F.: Probabilistic latent variable model to detect structure in binary data. (2022)

Warner, C., Sommer, F.: A Model for Image Segmentation in Retina. (2020)

#### Extras

I self-produced and engineered an album of original songs I wrote, performed and recorded. I operate a stealth startup exploring computational poetry and lyric analysis in phoneme space. I am passionate about mindfulness - with a growth mindset, geared towards embracing challenge.